And all the scientists -- (Laughter) yeah, all the scientists always laugh when I say that, because grant-writing never goes well. It is so hard; you're always pulling your hair out, trying to come up with that million-dollar-winning idea. But I realized that the grant-writing was going well, because I was able to focus and maintain my attention for longer than I had before. And my long-term memory -- what I was studying in my own lab -- seemed to be better in me. And that's when I put it together. Maybe all that exercise that I had included and added to my life was changing my brain. Maybe I did an experiment on myself without even knowing it. So as a curious neuroscientist, I went to the literature to see what I could find about what we knew about the effects of exercise on the brain. And what I found was an exciting and a growing literature that was essentially showing everything that I noticed in myself.
y todos los científicos... (Risas) Sí, todos los científicos siempre ríen cuando digo eso porque las investigaciones jamás van bien. Es tan difícil, uno siempre se está arrancando el cabello tratando de proponer una idea extraordinaria. pero me di cuenta de que la elaboración de la propuesta iba bien puesto que podía concentrarme y mantener mi atención por más tiempo que antes. Mi memoria a largo plazo era lo que estaba estudiando en mi propio laboratorio parecía estar mejor en mí. Y fue cuando uní las piezas. Tal vez todo el ejercicio que incluí y agregué a mi vida estaba cambiando mi mente, quizás hice un experimento en mí sin darme cuenta. Como neurocientífica curiosa, me dirigí a ver los estudios para saber qué es lo que sabíamos al respecto de los efectos del ejercicio en el cerebro. Encontré una fascinante y gran cantidad de estudios que esencialmente mostraban todo lo que yo notaba en mí.
Better mood, better energy, better memory, better attention. And the more I learned, the more I realized how powerful exercise was. Which eventually led me to the big decision to completely shift my research focus. And so now, after several years of really focusing on this question, I've come to the following conclusion:
Mejora de ánimo, más energía, mejora en la memoria y mayor atención. Entre más aprendía, más me daba cuenta de que el ejercicio era importante. Eventualmente, esto me dirigió a tomar una importante decisión a cambiar completamente el enfoque de mi investigación Ahora, después de varios años de enfocarme en esta pregunta, he llegado a la siguiente conclusión:
that exercise is the most transformative thing that you can do for your brain today for the following three reasons. Number one: it has immediate effects on your brain. A single workout that you do will immediately increase levels of neurotransmitters like dopamine, serotonin and noradrenaline. That is going to increase your mood right after that workout, exactly what I was feeling. My lab showed that a single workout can improve your ability to shift and focus attention, and that focus improvement will last for at least two hours. And finally, studies have shown that a single workout will improve your reaction times which basically means that you are going to be faster at catching that cup of Starbucks that falls off the counter, which is very, very important. (Laughter) But these immediate effects are transient, they help you right after. What you have to do is do what I did, that is change your exercise regime, increase your cardiorespiratory function, to get the long-lasting effects. And these effects are long-lasting because exercise actually changes the brain's anatomy, physiology and function. Let's start with my favorite brain area, the hippocampus. The hippocampus -- or exercise actually produces brand new brain cells, new brain cells in the hippocampus, that actually increase its volume, as well as improve your long-term memory, OK? And that including in you and me. Number two: the most common finding in neuroscience studies, looking at effects of long-term exercise, is improved attention function dependent on your prefrontal cortex. You not only get better focus and attention, but the volume of the hippocampus increases as well. And finally, you not only get immediate effects of mood with exercise but those last for a long time. So you get long-lasting increases in those good mood neurotransmitters. But really, the most transformative thing that exercise will do is its protective effects on your brain. Here you can think about the brain like a muscle. The more you're working out, the bigger and stronger your hippocampus and prefrontal cortex gets. Why is that important? Because the prefrontal cortex and the hippocampus are the two areas that are most susceptible to neurodegenerative diseases and normal cognitive decline in aging. So with increased exercise over your lifetime, you're not going to cure dementia or Alzheimer's disease, but what you're going to do is you're going to create the strongest, biggest hippocampus and prefrontal cortex so it takes longer for these diseases to actually have an effect. You can think of exercise, therefore, as a supercharged 401K for your brain, OK? And it's even better, because it's free. So this is the point in the talk where everybody says, "That sounds so interesting, Wendy, but I really will only want to know one thing. And that is, just tell me the minimum amount of exercise I need to get all these changes." (Laughter) And so I'm going to tell you the answer to that question. First, good news: you don't have to become a triathlete to get these effects. The rule of thumb is you want to get three to four times a week exercise minimum 30 minutes an exercise session, and you want to get aerobic exercise in. That is, get your heart rate up. And the good news is, you don't have to go to the gym to get a very expensive gym membership. Add an extra walk around the block in your power walk. You see stairs -- take stairs. And power-vacuuming can be as good as the aerobics class that you were going to take at the gym. So I've gone from memory pioneer to exercise explorer. From going into the innermost workings of the brain, to trying to understand how exercise can improve our brain function, and my goal in my lab right now is to go beyond that rule of thumb that I just gave you -- three to four times a week, 30 minutes. I want to understand the optimum exercise prescription for you, at your age, at your fitness level, for your genetic background, to maximize the effects of exercise today and also to improve your brain and protect your brain the best for the rest of your life. But it's one thing to talk about exercise, and it's another to do it. So I'm going to invoke my power as a certified exercise instructor, to ask you all to stand up. (Laughter) We're going to do just one minute of exercise. It's call-and-response, just do what I do, say what I say, and make sure you don't punch your neighbor, OK? Music! (Upbeat music) Five, six, seven, eight, it's right, left, right, left. And I say, I am strong now. Let's hear you. Audience: I am strong now. Wendy Suzuki: Ladies, I am Wonder Woman-strong. Let's hear you! Audience: I am Wonder Woman-strong. WS: New move -- uppercut, right and left. I am inspired now. You say it! Audience: I am inspired now. WS: Last move -- pull it down, right and left, right and left. I say, I am on fire now! You say it. Audience: I am on fire now. WS: And done! OK, good job! (Applause) Thank you. I want to leave you with one last thought. And that is, bringing exercise in your life will not only give you a happier, more protective life today, but it will protect your brain from incurable diseases. And in this way it will change the trajectory of your life for the better. Thank you very much. (Applause) Thank you.
El ejercicio es la actividad más transformadora que uno puede hacer hoy por su cerebro, por las siguientes tres razones. Número uno: tiene efectos inmediatos en el cerebro. Un solo ejercicio que uno realiza aumentará inmediatamente los niveles de neurotransmisores, como la dopamina, serotonina, y noradrenalina. Esto incrementa el estado de ánimo justo después del ejercicio, justo lo que yo estaba sintiendo. Mi equipo mostró que tan solo un ejercicio puede mejorar tu habilidad de adaptación y concentración, y esa mejora en la concentración durará por lo menos dos horas. Finalmente los estudios mostraron que un solo ejercicio mejorará tu tiempo de reacción lo que significa que tu serás la persona más rápida al recoger esa bebida de Starbucks que cae de la barra, lo cual es muy... muy importante. (Risas) Estos efectos inmediatos son efímeros, te ayudan al instante. Deben hacer lo que hice yo, cambiar el régimen de ejercicio, incrementar la función cardiorrespiratoria para obtener los efectos a largo plazo. Estos efectos son a largo plazo debido a que el ejercicio cambia la anatomía del cerebro, su psicología y función. Vamos a empezar con mi área favorita del cerebro: el hipocampo. El hipocampo... de hecho el ejercicio produce nuevas neuronas estas células en el hipocampo que ciertamente incrementan su volumen así como mejoran la memoria a largo plazo y eso nos incluye a Uds. y a mí. Número dos: el estudio más común en la neurociencia, observa los efectos del ejercicio a largo plazo, depende de la mejora en la atención o de la corteza prefrontal. No solo tendrán mejor concentración y atención sino que el volumen del hipocampo también aumentará. Por último, no solo habrá efectos directos en el estado de ánimo con el ejercicio estos durarán durante largo tiempo. Obtienen incrementos duraderos en los neurotransmisores del buen ánimo. Realmente la cosa más transformadora que logra el ejercicio son los efectos en el cerebro. Pueden ver al cerebro como un músculo, entre más lo ejerciten más grande y fuerte el hipocampo y la corteza prefrontal se volverán. ¿Por qué es importante? Porque la corteza prefrontal y el hipocampo son las dos áreas más susceptibles a enfermedades neurodegenerativas y a un declive normal cognitivo debido al envejecimiento. Al aumentar el ejercicio durante sus vidas no solo previenen la demencia o el Alzheimer sino que crearán los hipocampos y cortezas prefrontales más fuertes y grandes. De hecho, les toma más tiempo surgir a estas enfermedades. Pueden ver al ejercicio como un plan de retiro para el cerebro y es aún mejor, ya que es gratis. Este es el momento en la charla en el que todos dicen... "Esto suena muy interesante, Wendy pero yo solo quiero saber una cosa. Y es que me digas cuál es la cantidad mínima de ejercicio que necesito para obtener todos esos cambios". (Risas) Les diré la respuesta a esa pregunta: Primero, buenas noticias: no necesitan convertirse en triatleta. La regla de oro es hacer ejercicio tres a cuatro veces a la semana, rutinas de ejercicios de mínimo 30 minutos y agregar ejercicio aeróbico. Esto es, aumentar el ritmo cardíaco. La buena noticia es que no se requiere ir al gimnasio a obtener una membresía muy costosa. Sumen una vuelta extra alrededor de la cuadra en su caminata. Si ven escaleras, usen las escaleras. Usar la aspiradora puede ser tan buen ejercicio de aeróbics como el que podrían hacer en el gimnasio. Pasé de pionera en la memoria a estudiosa del ejercicio. De lo más recóndito del funcionamiento del cerebro a intentar comprender cómo el ejercicio puede mejorar los procesos cerebrales y en este momento mi propósito en el laboratorio es ir más allá de la regla de oro que les acabo de dar; 30 minutos, de 3 a 4 veces a la semana. Quiero entender la prescripción optima de ejercicio para ti, a tu edad, y de acuerdo a tu condición física, a tu historial genético, para maximizar los efectos del ejercicio en el presente. además de mejorar tu cerebro y protegerlo de la mejor manera por el resto de su vida. Pero, una cosa es hablar del ejercicio, y otra es hacerlo. Pues bien, voy a invocar mi poder como instructora certificada de ejercicio para pedirles a todos que se pongan de pie. (Risas) Vamos a hacer solo un minuto de ejercicio. Es "llama y responde", hagan lo que hago, digan lo que digo. y asegúrense de no golpear al de a lado, ¿está bien? ¡Música! (Música alegre) Cinco, seis, siete, ocho; derecha, izquierda, derecha, izquierda. Y digo: Ahora soy fuerte Ahora Uds... Público: Ahora soy fuerte. Wendy Suzuki: ¡Mujeres! Soy la poderosa mujer maravilla. ¡Quiero escucharlas! Público: Soy la poderosa mujer maravilla. WS: Nuevo movimiento, gancho, derecha e izquierda. Digan: Estoy inspirado ahora. Público: Estoy inspirado ahora. WS: Último movimiento, tiro hacia abajo, derecha e izquierda, derecha e izquierda. Yo digo: ¡Estoy haciéndolo muy bien! Ahora Uds. Público: ¡Estoy haciéndolo muy bien! WS: ¡Listo! ¡Bien hecho! (Aplausos) Gracias. Los quiero dejar una última idea y es: incluir el ejercicio en sus vidas no solo les hará felices sino que protegerá el cerebro de enfermedades incurables. De esta forma cambiará la trayectoria de sus vidas para mejor. Muchas gracias. (Aplausos) Gracias.